<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Bbplot on Biased</title>
    <link>/tags/bbplot/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Bbplot on Biased</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>Sean Meling Murray</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 13 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/tags/bbplot/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>#tidytuesday: Women in the workforce</title>
      <link>/2019/03/13/2019-03-13-tidytuesday-women-in-the-workforce/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2019/03/13/2019-03-13-tidytuesday-women-in-the-workforce/</guid>
      <description>Last week’s #tidytuesday data about women in the workforce is provided by the Bureau of Labor Statistics and the Census Bureau.
As usual, we start by skimming the data to get a quick overview:
# Setup library(tidyverse) library(skimr) # Loading data csv &amp;lt;- &amp;quot;~/Documents/Github/tidytuesday/data/2019/2019-03-05/jobs_gender.csv&amp;quot; jobs_gender &amp;lt;- read_csv(csv) jobs_gender %&amp;gt;% skim  There are some missing values in total_earnings_female (estimated median wages for females). There are also quite a few NA’s in wage_percent_of_male (female wages as percent of male wages), which according to the #tidytuesday repo indicates small sample sizes for those occupations.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>#tidytuesday: Special binary operators and plotting PhDs</title>
      <link>/2019/02/20/2019-02-20-tidytuesday-special-binary-operators-and-plotting-phds/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2019/02/20/2019-02-20-tidytuesday-special-binary-operators-and-plotting-phds/</guid>
      <description>If you’re familiar with the tidyverse, you’re most likely familiar with the pipe operator %&amp;gt;% from magrittr. The pipe operators
 pipe their left-hand side values forward into expressions that appear on the right-hand side, i.e. one can replace f(x) with x %&amp;gt;% f(), where %&amp;gt;% is the (main) pipe-operator (https://magrittr.tidyverse.org/).
 %&amp;gt;% is an example of a special binary operator. Now, what’s cool about special binary operators is that we can define our own!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>#tidytuesday: Skimr, regular expressions and recessions</title>
      <link>/2019/02/08/2019-02-08-tidytuesday-skimr-regular-expressions-and-recessions/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 08 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2019/02/08/2019-02-08-tidytuesday-skimr-regular-expressions-and-recessions/</guid>
      <description>This week’s post will mark the start of my experimentation with purrr and regular expressions (regex). I’ll also take a look at a package called skimr, which looks like a pretty efficient way to get a quick overview of our data.
In case you don’t know, purrr essentially abstracts away the need for many kinds of for loops used to iterate over lists or atomic vectors. As Hadley writes in R for Data Science, the apply family of functions solve a similar problem, but purrr provides a more consistent and easier-to-learn approach.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>#tidytuesday: Making BBC style plots with bbplot</title>
      <link>/2019/02/03/2019-02-03-tidytuesday-making-bbc-style-plots-with-bbplot/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 03 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2019/02/03/2019-02-03-tidytuesday-making-bbc-style-plots-with-bbplot/</guid>
      <description>I must admit that I wasn’t too excited about this week’s #tidytuesday dataset from the United States Department of Agriculture (USDA) concerning cows and milk products. I thought I might give it a rest this week, but then I stumbled across a post on r/rstats linking to this Medium post by the folks at the BBC’s department for visual and data journalism.
In brief, the post describes how the team transitioned from exploring data using ggplot2, to using the tidyverse to produce publication-ready plots.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>