<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Tidytuesday on Biased</title>
    <link>/tags/tidytuesday/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Tidytuesday on Biased</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>Sean Meling Murray</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 08 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/tags/tidytuesday/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>#tidytuesday: Skimr, regular expressions and recessions</title>
      <link>/2019/02/08/2019-02-08-tidytuesday-skimr-regular-expressions-and-recessions/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 08 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2019/02/08/2019-02-08-tidytuesday-skimr-regular-expressions-and-recessions/</guid>
      <description>This week’s post will mark the start of my experimentation with purrr and regular expressions (regex). I’ll also take a look at a package called skimr, which looks like a pretty efficient way to get a quick overview of our data.
In case you don’t know, purrr essentially abstracts away the need for many kinds of for loops used to iterate over lists or atomic vectors. As Hadley writes in R for Data Science, the apply family of functions solve a similar problem, but purrr provides a more consistent and easier-to-learn approach.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>#tidytuesday: Making BBC style plots with bbplot</title>
      <link>/2019/02/03/2019-02-03-tidytuesday-making-bbc-style-plots-with-bbplot/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 03 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2019/02/03/2019-02-03-tidytuesday-making-bbc-style-plots-with-bbplot/</guid>
      <description>I must admit that I wasn’t too excited about this week’s #tidytuesday dataset from the United States Department of Agriculture (USDA) concerning cows and milk products. I thought I might give it a rest this week, but then I stumbled across a post on r/rstats linking to this Medium post by the folks at the BBC’s department for visual and data journalism.
In brief, the post describes how the team transitioned from exploring data using ggplot2, to using the tidyverse to produce publication-ready plots.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>#tidytuesday: Exploring (missing) data with maps</title>
      <link>/2019/01/27/2019-01-26-tidy-tuesday-2-plotting-geospatial-data-with-ggplot2/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 27 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2019/01/27/2019-01-26-tidy-tuesday-2-plotting-geospatial-data-with-ggplot2/</guid>
      <description>This week’s #tidytuesday data is the incarceration trends data set from the Vera Institute of Justice, which contains county-level jail data (1970-2015) and prison data (1983-2015). Vera is a non-profit research and policy organisation focusing on “the causes and consequences of mass incarceration, racial disparities, and the loss of public trust in law enforcement” (see the Wikipedia article for more).
I’ve been thinking about exploring maps in R but never gotten around to it, so this seemed like a great opportunity.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>First foray into Tidy Tuesday</title>
      <link>/2019/01/22/2019-01-22-first-foray-into-tidytuesday/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2019/01/22/2019-01-22-first-foray-into-tidytuesday/</guid>
      <description>This week was my Tidy Tuesday debut! Tidy Tuesday is a weekly data project which is aimed at R users who want to practice their wrangling and visualisation skills within the tidyverse. This week’s data set features a historical record of rocket launches, and formed the basis for the article “The space race is dominated by new contenders”.
My goals for this week were to:
 Expose myself to gganimate, a really nifty package that extends ggplot2 to include animations.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>